# Ponaganti Tulasi Ram

Data Scientist / Analyst Cergy,France/+33(0)769492265

Email: ponagantit.cytech@gmail.com / tulasiram.ponaganti@yahoo.com

• <u>LINKEDIN</u> • <u>GITHUB</u> • <u>MEDIUM</u>



#### PROFILE

Proven Professional fellow with years of experience in Structured Query Language and database management systems. I completed a Master's in Big Data at CY-TECH University which drove me to learn knowledge in machine learning and deep learning techniques. Data Scientist Intern at Volvo challenged me to prove all my skills. I am a competitor and passionate engineer challenged to solve complex problems and an enthusiast to learn new tools and technology. I contribute to data science communities and learn new skills in coding, analysis, and algorithms implementation. I am a curious professional programmer and analyst to identify use cases from the raw data and transform them into business revenue. I have expertise in optimization of time with good communication skills, contributing with team members, working towards the same goals for the success of a team.

#### PROFESSIONAL AND TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Time Management, Project Management, Problem-Solving, Communication, On-time Delivery, Client-Oriented
- Python, R Programming, PySpark, SQL, Advanced Statistics, Data Analysis, Pre-processing, Model evaluation and validation, Feature Engineering, Machine Learning, NLP, Computer Vision, AWS, Microsoft Azure
- Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, TensorFlow, Open CV, Scikit-Learn, Flask API, Django, Beautiful soup4, Twint, NLTK, Genism, BERT.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### DATA SCIENTIST / ANALYST, SELF-EMPLOYMENT, FRANCE (MAR 2021 - NOV 2021)

Developed E-commerce backend machine learning project using python open-source libraries which has recommendation
properties to pop up products for clients and get their cost values with help of assistant bot to make easier shopping to
clients.

#### DATA SCIENTIST INTERN, VOLVO GROUP, FRANCE (SEP 2019 - MAR 2020)

Developed PySpark code on Azure platform to build Volvo dictionary and integrate them to find similar documents
from different databases to optimize the workflow of Volvo dealers. Designed and planned a system for automatic
recognition of failure parts (sensors) in trucks and provided solutions for the service of stakeholders. Developed and
implemented preprocessing pipeline and model the data, implemented word embeddings, document level
embeddings, state of the art model BERT.

### DATA ANALYST, INFOTECH SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS, INDIA (SEP 2015 - NOV 2016)

Providing solutions with data visualization techniques using BI tools. Developing the reports for the stakeholders to gain
profits with different kinds of products. Communicated with different domains of clients to understand the terminology of
gross products. An increase in the profit margin of the product by 15% within six months. Exceeded annual sales goals by
10% and was recognized as the best performing professional

### JUNIOR DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR, ITC INFOTECH, INDIA (JUL 2013 – FEB 2015)

Managed and completed Exadata V2 POC migrating data from UDB2 Marketing database to Oracle RAC on Exa data
achieving up to 20 times better query performance. Implemented and documented cloning procedure for Oracle database
running on Linux using ASM. Successfully deployed OEM cloud control and MySQL Enterprise dashboard into the
company's network tfully automate database and system monitoring.

### DATABASE DEVELOPER, GENPACT, INDIA (JUL 2010 – FEB 2013)

Experience developing enterprise applications with several database technologies, including SQL Server, Oracle PL/SQL.
Contributed with all the departments for creating and modifying databases using complex queries. Designed relational
database and programmed all database code. Responsible for user access credentials and modifications of data using
PL/SQL queries.

#### **EDUCATION**

MASTERS IN BIGDATA, EISTI (CY-TECH), CERGY, PARIS, FRANCE (2017 - 2020)
BACHELORS IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, ANDHRA UNIVERSITY, INDIA (2006 - 2010)

## TECHNICAL PROJECTS (https://github.com/ram574?tab=repositories)

- 2021 KAGGLE MACHINE LEARNING AND DATA SCIENCE SURVEY
- STRIVING FOR CARBON NEUTRALITY BY 2050
- PREDICTING TEST SCORES OF STUDENTS (SUPERVISED ML)
- REPAIR SOLUTION ENGINE FOR VOLVO TRUCKS USING NLP
- COVID DATA EXPLORATION AND ANALYSIS
- TITANIC PREDICTIONS AND BOSTON HOUSING ANALYSIS
- IMAGE CLASSIFICATION USING TENSORFLOW AND KERAS
- DETECTING-DEPRESSION-IN-SOCIAL-MEDIA-VIA-TWITTER-USAGE
- MULTI-LABEL TEXT CLASSIFICATION USING KERAS
- ANAMOLY DETECTION USING UNSUPERVISED MACHINE LEARNING
- STOCK MARKET PREDICTION DASHBOARD
- SENTIMENT ANALYSIS USING CONVOLUTIONAL NEURAL NETWORK
- SARCASTIC CHATBOT USING TENSORFLOW
- IMDB REVIEWS RECOMMENDATION SYSTEM
- HOMICIDE CRIMES ANALYSIS IN POWER BI

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

OPENCV, TENSORFLOW 2.0, MATPLOTLIB, SEABORN, MACHINE LEARNING

#### **LANGUAGES**